MedicalTermsQuestions = [
    {
        "question": "The root word for lung is ____",
        "answer": "pulm/pneumo",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for liver is ____",
        "answer": "hepato",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for gall/bile is ____",
        "answer": "chol/e",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for nose is ____",
        "answer": "rhino",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for head/brain is ____",
        "answer": "cephalo",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for mouth is ____",
        "answer": "stomato",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for ear is ____",
        "answer": "oto",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for heart is ____",
        "answer": "cardio",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for large intestines is ____",
        "answer": "colo",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for anus is ____",
        "answer": "procto",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for small intestines is ____",
        "answer": "entero",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for ovary is ____",
		"answer": "oophoro",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for uterus is ____",
        "answer": "hystero/metro",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for testis is ____",
        "answer": "orchido",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for falopian tube is ____",
        "answer": "salpingo",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word for bladder is ____",
        "answer": "cysto",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word hemo/emia means ____",
        "answer": "blood",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word phlebo/veno means ____",
        "answer": "vein",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word dento means ____",
        "answer": "teeth",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word gingivo means ____",
        "answer": "gums",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word glosso/linguo means ____",
        "answer": "tongue",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word masto/mammo means ____",
        "answer": "breast",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word mening/o means ____ surrounding the brain and spinal cord",
        "answer": "membranes",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word myel/o means ____",
        "answer": "spinal cord/bone marrow",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word oseto means ____",
        "answer": "bone",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word brady means ____",
		"answer": "slow",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The root word tachy means ____",
        "answer": "fast",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix -pnea means ____",
        "answer": "breath",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix -algia means ____",
        "answer": "pain",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix -uria means ____",
        "answer": "urine",
        "type": "fill"
	},
    {
        "question": "The root word for kidneys is ____",
        "answer": "rene/nephro",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix -megaly means ____",
        "answer": "enlarged",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The prefix -pne/u means ____",
        "answer": "lung",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The prefix -algesia means ____",
        "answer": "pain",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The prefix -ur/o means ____",
        "answer": "urine",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The prefix mega means ____",
        "answer": "enlarged",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix -itis means ____",
        "answer": "inflammation",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix -pathy means ____",
        "answer": "disease",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix -iasis means ____",
        "answer": "abnormal",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The suffix -osis means ____",
        "answer": "abnormal",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The prefix -dys means ____",
		"answer": "painful",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -ectomy means to ____ out",
        "answer": "cut",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -otomy means to ____ into",
        "answer": "cut",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -ostomy means to make a ____",
        "answer": "mouth",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -stasis means to ____",
        "answer": "stop",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -cyte means ____",
        "answer": "cell",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -rrhea means ____",
        "answer": "flow",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -plasia means ____",
        "answer": "growth",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term a/an means ____",
        "answer": "without",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -ptysis means ____",
        "answer": "cough",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -plasty means ____",
        "answer": "reconstruction",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term angi/o means ____",
        "answer": "vessel",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term emes/o means ____",
        "answer": "vomit",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term lith/o means ____",
        "answer": "stone",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term olig/o means ____",
		"answer": "less",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term melan/o means ____",
        "answer": "black",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term xanth/o means ____",
        "answer": "yellow",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term poli/o means ____",
        "answer": "grey",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term eosin/o means ____",
        "answer": "orange",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "A patient has been diagnosed as having an enlarged liver. The doctor describes it as ____",
		"choices": "megacolon, hepatomegaly, macrostomia, hepatitis, gastroenteritis",
        "answer": "hepatomegaly",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "A patient has had a diagnosis of colon cancer and will need surgical removal of the colon. She will end up with a permanent hole in her abdomen for drainage into a bag. The permanent opening is called a ____",
        "choices": "megacolon, colitis, colonoscopy, colectomy",
		"answer": "colostomy",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "You have taken your friend to the emergency room for frequent painful sensation while urinating. After examination and lab tests, the physician reports that your friend has an inflammation of bladder and makes a diagnosis of ____",
        "choices": "hepatitis, cystitis, proctitis, nephritis, orchiditis",
		"answer": "cystitis",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Bradycardia is a term describing ____",
		"choices": "fast heart rate, inflammation of heart muscle, slow breathing, slow heart rate, small heart",
        "answer": "slow heart rate",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term -oma means ____",
        "answer": "swelling",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term aden/o means ____",
        "answer": "gland",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term my/o means ____",
        "answer": "muscle",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term lymph/o means ____ tissue",
        "answer": "lymph",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term carcin/o means ____",
        "answer": "malignant",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term osteo means ____",
		"answer": "bone",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term melan/o means ____",
        "answer": "melanocytes",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term endo means ____",
        "answer": "within",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term peri/circum means ____",
        "answer": "around",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term epi means on ____",
        "answer": "top  ",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "The term trans means ____",
        "answer": "through",
        "type": "fill"
    },
    {
        "question": "A tumor of the protective membranes surrounding the brain and spinal cord is called a/an ____",
		"choices": "neuroma, encephalocele, myeloma, meningioma, meningocele",
        "answer": "meningioma",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Frequently getting up and urinating during the night is described as ____",
		"choices": "nocturia, enuresis, uremia, oliguria",
        "answer": "nocturia",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "A lab report comes back to a physician documenting numerous erythrocytes in the urine specimen. The term for this is ____",
		"choices": "oliguria, polyuria, anuria, hematuria, nocturia",
        "answer": "hematuria",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Patients with pneumonia often find it difficult or painful to take deep breaths. The term for this is ____",
		"choices": "tachypnea, dyspnea, apnea, epistaxis",
        "answer": "dyspnea",
        "type": "multiple"
    }
]